First off, there's something
I'd like to say.
You look pretty good in that uniform.
If it's
to save you
I don't care
how many times
I die
Why, thank you!
Hearing you say that tells me that recreating
it from your memories was worthwhile.
So what is this place?
As one who is qualified,
you entered the graveyard.
Thus the trial began.
That's all there is to it.
Didn't you hear me say, "First,
you need to face your own past"?
I'm gradually starting to remember.
What did you do to me?
I had completely forgotten about you.
It was quicker to meddle with your memories
than it would've been to trust
that you could keep a secret.
And? Did I pass the trial?
Having seen every moment of it,
I think the result you
achieved was more than suitable.
Every moment? Wait, you—
"I'm so sorry!"
When you said that, even I teared up a bit.
Shut up! Don't tell anyone
about that! It's too embarrassing!
Anyway, so this world is actually...
Yes, that's right.
It's a fabricated world
that I recreated with utmost
faithfulness to your memories.
Everything, including your parents. Understand?
You fabricated all that? Really?
But some stuff was mentioned
that even I didn't know.
Are you sure you didn't know?
Did you never once entertain
the thought of your father
being different in any way
from what you'd pictured?
Did you really think you could
hide the parts of your heart
that you thought no one knew about?
The desire to have them know,
so you'd feel less burdened...
The selfish wish that they'd still
love you, even if they knew...
Can you state with certainty that
you did not seek any of that
from your imaginary parents?
That would be far too idealistic,
not to mention convenient.
Don't you agree?
Don't make fun of my parents, Echidna.
What?
I gave all of my answers,
and both my mom and my dad accepted them.
They told me to give it
my all, and to take care.
Their voices, their smiles,
and everything else
shattered what I had imagined.
My parents are too big to even
fit in my puny imagination!
Don't underestimate them!
I told them everything I wanted to say.
I'm not gonna let anything
you say sidetrack me.
This trial is over, in the truest sense.
I look forward to seeing how
you handle the next question.
Wait, "next question"?
What does that mean?
There's more than one trial?!
There are three graveyard trials in total.
You must pass all of them
to set the Sanctuary free.
I'm so glad I finally got to tell you this!
Seeing you so surprised makes my heart leap.
It's already starting to disappear.
If you go outside,
you should find yourself back in the graveyard.
Hey, Echidna...
What is it? You want me to let you hit me?
You do have that right, it's true.
But I'm a girl. My face is—
Thanks.
Even if they weren't real...
Even if I didn't get to say
it to my real parents...
It's thanks to you that I got
to say what I wanted to say.
So...
Thanks.
You are a very intriguing human.
I just can't comprehend you.
It actually frightens me.
It's an honor to know I can frighten a witch.
Oh, yeah.
It sounded like you really want
me to go through the next trial,
but I can't grant that wish for you.
Meaning?
I'm not the one who'll pass the
trials and set the Sanctuary free.
Someone else is gonna grant that wish for you.
Is that so? I wonder...
Where...
Oh, right. I went through the trial.
Emilia!
Emilia?! Hey, hang in there!
Emilia! Emilia!
Subaru?
Right... I was undergoing
the trial... and...
Emilia?
I-I'm... It wasn't me!
Huh?
It wasn't! And yet...
I keep telling you it wasn't me, and yet...
Hey, calm down!
Look at me, Emilia!
No! Don't look at me like that!
No! No!
It wasn't me!
It's okay! Come on, it's okay!
...me all alone...
I'm with you! I'm here!
I won't leave you alone!
It's okay!
Father...
Help me!
Puck...
Puck!
She's finally calmed down,
and is resting now.
The aroma hypnosis will prevent any nightmares.
Sorry to put you through the trouble.
I didn't do it for you.
Still, the Sanctuary is even
farther from being set free now.
Um, may I say something?
What's up, Otto?
It might be possible to get
everyone outside the barrier
without doing the trial and
freeing the Sanctuary.
Huh? What're you talkin' about?
There's no way in hell.
Just hear me out.
I know that anyone of mixed blood who
touches the barrier loses consciousness.
I saw it with my own eyes.
So...
Why don't those of us
who aren't affected by the barrier
carry the others through it
while they're unconscious?
I get it! That way, we could get everyone—
An amusing idea, but one you
would be better off not trying.
I would rather not become
an empty shell of a soul.
You're that girl from—
Ow, ow, ow!
Barusu, here's your tea.
Tea, my ass! That's hot!
You're gonna burn my cheek off!
I didn't know what was going on!
So dramatic. What a pathetic
excuse for a man.
Avoid making any unnecessary comments.
Ram, get me some tea, too.
It's coarse tea.
Don't you usually talk more humble-like?
I just brewed some leaves I picked up.
Show your gratitude to me for making it
by drinking every last drop.
I heard you had brought in more
people from outside, Young Gar.
What a noisy boy he is.
Um... And you are...
I am Ryuzu Bilma.
It is my duty, you might say,
to represent this community,
though I am old and frail, as you can see.
As we can see?
So you're what they call a loli hag?
I figured I'd meet one eventually,
but you really fit the stereotype.
How dare you call me an old woman
when we've only just met.
Well, no matter.
And you are Barusu... which makes you Young Su.
Young Su?
So, Ryuzu-san, what makes
you say my idea won't work?
Something about an "empty shell of a soul"?
Have you not heard?
When one of mixed blood touches the barrier,
it takes away their consciousness.
More specifically, it repels their soul.
Repels their soul? Uh...
So when a mixed-blood tries to force
their way through the barrier,
their soul is separated from their body,
and only their soul remains inside
the barrier, leaving an empty shell, right?
Ah, you do catch on quickly.
That is the gist of it, yes.
When a body without a soul exits the barrier,
it is, in other words, dead.
Dead?
This tea's gross!
It tastes like grass!
Did you actually make it with grass?
Still, if the qualification to undergo
the trial is having mixed blood,
doesn't that mean you or Garfiel
could do it if you wanted to?
If we are speaking only of making the attempt,
it stands to reason that we could.
But we cannot free the Sanctuary.
That is the contract that
has been handed down
among us residents of the
Sanctuary for generations.
Subaru?
Morning, Emilia-tan.
Did you sleep well?
Morning...
Did you stay with me all night?
I wouldn't have been able to
sleep in my room, anyway.
Otto talks in his sleep, you know.
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I really lost my composure in the graveyard.
Oh, don't worry about it.
More importantly...
I-It's not like that!
What? That's funny... Why did I...
Are you finally getting assertive enough
to reach out for me subconsciously?!
No, no, it's not like that at all!
I think I just wasn't thinking...
You denied that so fast! And you
"weren't thinking"? Really?!
I mean...
As long as you can smile, it's all right.
You can undergo the trial again tonight.
Again... tonight...
I need to tell you something, Barusu.
Not all of the residents are in favor
of setting the Sanctuary free.
What do you mean?
Only the heavy-handed people like Garf,
led by Ryuzu-sama, are pushing for its freedom.
There is a conservative faction that
doesn't want the Sanctuary to be freed.
There are people who don't want it set free?
The conservatives believe that having
minimal interaction with outsiders is ideal.
In their opinion, destroying that
will cause nothing but trouble.
I get Garfiel, but they
don't even trust Ryuzu-san?
Or Frederica, either.
It was Frederica who gave
Emilia-sama the glowing stone.
So you think Frederica started this whole thing?
Circumstantial evidence suggests that
Frederica has some plan in mind.
As it is, Emilia-sama escaped
disaster by a hair's breadth,
thanks to your noble...
your relatively noble sacrifice.
You didn't have to amend that.
I mean, I didn't sacrifice myself,
so you can amend that, but...
Just be careful, Barusu.
To the ones who oppose
setting the Sanctuary free,
the best way to assure they get what
they want is to harm Emilia-sama.
You never know who might be your enemy.
Be alert at all times.
C'mon, Ram, join us.
The hell? You're no fun.
Do you like Ram or something?
Well, she's hot, ain't she?
Nothin' unusual about a guy bein'
attracted to a strong, capable girl.
I hope it works out better this time.
We don't want a short nap for a morolok to
be a whole day's sleep for the rest of us.
Is there something you want to do
after getting out of the barrier?
Well, that came outta nowhere.
What do I wanna do once I'm outside?
A guy who can come and go as he pleases
wouldn't have a clue how the old hag and I feel.
What about Frederica?
Huh?
What does Frederica think
about the Sanctuary?
Didn't she tell you a damn thing?
She only said she couldn't
explain it to me in detail.
All she told me about you was your name,
because of some oath.
Oath, my ass.
Hah! Talk about a handy excuse.
Sounds just like her damn master.
Are you and Frederica not
even that close at all?
If you're askin' whether we get along or not,
nope, we don't.
Anyway, when you were in the
graveyard yesterday, didn't you—
Emilia!
I'm sorry! I... I...
...again...
I see. That is unfortunate.
Still, just learning that you cannot lose
your right to undergo the trial is something.
Well? What did you call me in here
without Emilia to talk about?
Just a bit of conspiracy.
I am not so big-hearted that I would
invite one who cannot be trusted.
Can't be trusted? Are you
talking about Emilia?
What the heck are you—
Be calm, Subaru-kun.
I would like you to continue to help and
support Emilia-sama as you always have.
You don't have to ask me to do that.
But what are you going to do?
The same, naturally.
I will give my utmost to help
Emilia-sama win the royal selection.
What I mean to say is that
we are partners in crime.
Shouldn't you just say we're partners?
You keep contradicting yourself.
Oh? And what might that—
Quit playing dumb!
Everyone knew the Witch's Cult
would start causing trouble
when Emilia's participation
was announced to the public!
And what the hell were you doing?!
You hid information about the
Witch's Cult from Emilia, didn't you?!
Emilia didn't know anything!
If she had, everything would've been different!
And if it had...
that wouldn't have...
You should've been there.
If you had been there,
that wouldn't have happened.
If you had been protecting everyone...
But you fulfilled my role in my absence.
As a knight, your performance
was commendable.
Who gives a—
Calm down, Barusu.
Ram, you're okay with all this?!
You were left behind at the
mansion like a sacrificial pawn!
I condone everything that Roswaal-sama did.
No matter how I was treated, even if
I was cast aside, that wouldn't change.
Then you're fine with Rem being sacrificed
for a stupid reason like that?!
I don't know who you're talking about,
but the name of a stranger
means nothing to me.
Why did I conceal information that
I should have disclosed to Emilia-sama?
Why was I not present at the mansion
when the Witch's Cult was preparing to attack?
There is but one answer to all these questions.
To ensure that I would not have to
confront the Witch's Cult myself,
I personally...
led these events to happen.
After all, if I had solved
the problem myself,
there would be no way for Emilia-sama,
nor you, to claim any credit.
It had a tremendous effect, did it not?
The attitudes of the villagers
of Arlam toward Emilia-sama
are drastically different than they
were before the Witch's Cult attacked.
They now see her not as an incomprehensible
relative of the witch,
but as one who contributed
to saving their lives.
Do you... have any idea what you're saying?!
That's only how it looks in hindsight!
Do you know how many people died
because you weren't there,
and didn't tell anyone anything?!
I do express my condolences for all
those on our side who were lost.
Or would you rather hear me apologize?
No! No! No! No! That's not it!
That's not what I want!
If I was still useless trash
that couldn't do anything,
what would you have done?!
If none of the villagers,
or Emilia, could've been saved—
I had faith...
in you.
I trusted that you would do anything
in your power for Emilia-sama,
give your best effort in establishing
an alliance with Crusch-sama,
put your life on the line to
stop the Witch Cult's attack,
and that you would complete all
of these tasks with excellence.
What the hell do you know about me?!
When I last saw you, I was absolute trash!
I only got a little less useless because
of all that happened after that!
And no one else even has any
idea what happened after that!
What made you believe in me?!
It appears tonight's conversation
has reached its end.
By the way, if you tell Emilia-sama
what we have discussed...
As if I could ever tell her!
Even overcome by such outrage,
deep down, you understand that
all is as it should be.
That for the sake of her chances
in the royal selection,
it would not do to create friction between
her and myself or the villagers.
I knew you would make a fitting
partner in crime for me.
I'm sorry. I failed again.
You don't have to beat yourself up so much.
It looks like you can't lose your
right to undergo the trial,
so it all just depends on
your own feelings now.
My own feelings...
I can tell this has been hard on you.
But there's no point in freeing the
Sanctuary if you're not the one to do it...
I think.
Think you can try again...
to make that happen?
Subaru, you jerk.
Wait, why the sudden abuse?!
When you ask with such gentle eyes and words,
how could I say I can't do it?
I'm not very smart,
but I do know that this is my duty.
Don't spoil me. Just believe in me.
I mean, I know I'm probably not
very convincing right now—
That's not true! I'll be waiting,
and believing in you!
Good. Thank you.
But I know I'll be causing trouble
for the people of Arlam.
That's the one thing I regret.
Oh, about that...
Would you mind leaving all that to me?
All right. I trust you.
I wouldn't start doubting
you now, after all this.
I trust you.
Anyway, I'm impressed you were
able to convince Garfiel.
It took two whole days, though.
He understands that since Emilia
is already inside the barrier,
setting the people of Arlam Village
free won't cause any problems.
I was sure he was the type that would
never listen to what we had to say.
For a trader, you're a pretty
lousy judge of character.
That's quite an old-fashioned
good luck charm.
Petra gave it to me before we left.
Right after Frederica hired her as a new maid.
Frederica would never do anything
mean to a new recruit.
She would never be that fiendish.
You don't need to worry about the girl.
Do you have faith in Frederica or not?
I can't tell.
I don't know what she's planning,
but Frederica is Frederica.
I have no doubt about that.
Also, I have a message from Roswaal-sama.
If you're worried about
having to face Frederica,
turn to Beatrice-sama.
And tell her this:
"Roswaal said to ask the question."
Question?
I don't know the details.
But when Beatrice-sama hears those words,
everything will change.
That's what Roswaal-sama said.
Subaru!
Hey.
Um... was I interrupting
your conversation with Ram?
Nah, no problem.
We weren't talking about anything important.
Besides, you take priority!
That makes me really happy,
but you should give priority
to the villagers right now.
Sure.
May the blessing of the spirits be with you.
Thanks for volunteering to take
us as far as the barrier.
It's fine, man.
Anyway, small fry...
You went through a trial at
the graveyard, didn't you?
You don't have to hide it.
I can tell.
And what's the point in asking me this?
It's simple.
You can go through the trial
in Emilia-sama's place.
I can't! The precedent would—
Is it really even necessary
to overcome your past?
I watched Emilia-sama go through the trial.
I saw how it broke her.
And every time, she comes
back totally freaked out.
I can't stand to watch it.
I have faith that Emilia can
make it through the trial.
So I—
You can expect what you want from her.
But does she really want to overcome her past?
When she cries about how scared she is,
ain't that how she really feels?
How Emilia... really feels?
Does Emilia actually...
Barrier's close now.
This is as far as I can take ya.
Take this.
This is...
I'm not gonna tell you my reasons.
But if you don't come back,
we're gonna be the ones suffering.
Show it to Frederica if push comes to shove.
It's okay.
No one's here?
What's going on?
Rem... What about Rem?
Rem!
You promised, didn't you?
That you'd take good care of
your bowels until we met again.
A Step Forward